Welcome back to a push in under 3
minutes. No time for intros. Let's get
into it. I feel like throughout this
entire unit, all I've done is talk about
how the rich are living gray and the
poor are not. And yes, that is true, but
there are quite a few people outside of
the top of the top and the bottom of the
bottom that actually benefited from the
guilded age. This group of people would
be the new emerging middle class. Let me
tell you why this middle class actually
formed. Going back to this triangle, you
have the ultra rich up at the top and
the povertystricken factory workers at
the bottom. But those weren't the only
two jobs that were needed in this era.
Big businesses like factories also
require a lot of white collar work,
meaning things like managers,
accountants, clerks, typists,
secretaries, salespeople, etc. were
needed. And these jobs paid better than
factory work and were way safer. Most of
the clerical work that was available at
a lower level will actually mostly be
taken by the women in society. The other
thing this ties into is education. Lots
of these jobs require a formal education
to understand them, which is where the
moral act of 1862 comes in. This act
gave federal land to states, and in
exchange, the states would use the land
to build institutions like colleges to
teach all the skills needed for these
white collar jobs. This is where we
start seeing teacher training or
business education and a new importance
to professional credentials. And also,
since there's now actually a decent
amount of people in the middle class
with disposable income and leisure time,
the first modern consumer culture
develops. things like amusement parks
such as Coney Island or maybe department
stores or a plethora of other things.
Also, let's talk about the rich really
quickly. Social Darwinism argued that
inequality between the rich and the poor
is natural, which mainly just gave poor
people another reason to resent the
wealthy. So, specifically, one man, my
boy Andrew Carnegie, saw this and
decided to create a new ideology and
called it his quote gospel of wealth.
This book doesn't reject anything new.
In fact, it openly accepts inequality,
capitalism, and elite dominance as
natural. What it does differently is add
a moral responsibility. The big argument
of this book is that the rich deserve
their wealth, but they must use it
wisely for the public good. And believe
it or not, it for the most part actually
works. This idea will cause
contributions that create libraries,
universities, museums, hospitals, and
lots more urban improvements. So, at
least one person on our big three list
is doing good for the world. Just one
though. On the screen now are AP style
questions for this topic. Pause now.
I'll put the answers on the screen now.
I will see you in the next one.